个人原创字幕
制作人：No One
一切就绪了吗
ls everything in place ?
（追踪程序：运行中）
今天不应该是你接我的班
You weren 't supposed to relieve me.
我知道，但是我就是想接
l know, but l felt like taking a shift.
你喜欢他，对吗？ 喜欢观察他
You like him, don 't you? You like watching him.
别胡说了
Don 't be ridiculous.
我们这样会害死他的 你明白吗？
We're gonna kill him. You understand?
墨菲斯相信他就是救世主
Morpheus believes he is the One.
你相信吗？
Do you?
我怎么想不重要
lt doesn't matter what l believe.
你不这么想，对吗？
You don 't, do you?
-你听见了吗？-听见什么？
-Did you hear that? -Hear what?
你确定这条线路安全吗？
Are you sure this line is clean ?
我当然确定了
Yeah, of course l'm sure.
我得走了
l better go.
303号房间
（暗合了基督教中圣父、圣子、圣灵“三位一体”Trinity 的概念，对应了电影开场崔尼蒂出现在此地
代码“HTTP 303”亦用于将Web 应用程序重定向到新 URI，对应抵抗者通过房间里的电话线从矩阵中转移回现实世界）
-别动！警察！-双手抱头！
-Freeze! Police! -Hands on your head !
快点！立即抱头！
Do it! Do it now!
Heart O' The City Hotel
（城市之心旅馆）
-警督 -哦，该死
-Lieutenant. -Oh , shit.
警督，给你下过明确的命令了
Lieutenant, you were given specific orders.
嘿，我只是照例行事
Hi, I'm just doing my job.
少跟我讲“我说的就是法律”的废话，趁早闭嘴吧
You give me that "juris-my-dick-tion"
crap, you can cram it up your ass.
命令是为了保护你们的安全
The orders were for your protection.
我想我们还是对付得了一个小姑娘的
I think we can handle one Iittle girl.
我派了两队人上去！
I sent two units!
他们很快就会把她带下来！
They're bringing her down now!
不，警督，你的人已经死了
No, Lieutenant, your men are already dead.
该死
Shit.
墨菲斯，线路被追踪到了，不知道是怎么做到的
Morpheus, the line was traced.
I don't know how.
我知道 他们切断了电话线
l know. They cut the hard line.
没时间了，你必须走其他出口
There's no time, you're gonna have to get to another exit.
-特工来了吗？ -是的
-Are there any agents? -Yes.
天杀的
Goddamn it.
你得集中注意，崔尼蒂
You have to focus, Trinity.
Wells与Lake的路口有个公共电话
There's a phone at Wells and Lake.
你能做到的
You can make it.
-好吧 -去吧
-All right. -Go.
这不可能
That's impossible.
快起来，崔尼蒂 站起来
Get up, Trinity. Just get up.
起来
Get up.
她跑了
She got out.
没关系
It doesn't matter.
-线人是可靠的 -是的
-The informant is real. -Yes.
我们知道他们下一个目标的名字了
We have the name of their next target.
名字是尼奥
The name is Neo.
我们需要尽快展开搜索
We'll need a search running.
已经在查了
It has already begun.
醒醒，尼奥
什么？
What?
矩阵奴役着你
什么鬼？
What the hell?
“跟着白兔走”
"Follow the white rabbit."
有人敲门，尼奥
什么人？
Who is it?
是Choi
It's Choi.
好吧
Yeah. Yeah.
101号房间
（尼奥的公寓是101，暗示他成为the One 的命运
可能源自于奥威尔《1984》中的设定：101号房是囚犯遭受最恐怖的心理折磨的地方 对应尼奥在这里夜夜难眠）
你晚来了两个小时
You're two hours late.
我知道 都是她的错
I know. It's her fault.
带钱了吗？
You got the money?
两千块
Two grand.
等着
Hold on.
（此书名为Simulacras and Simulation 《假象与模拟》，是一本1981 年出版的哲学论文，尼奥翻开的这一章是On Nihilism，即“论虚无主义”）
哈利路亚
Hallelujah.
你真是我的救主，伙计 我本人的耶稣基督
You're my savior, man. My own personal Jesus Christ.
要是你被逮到使用它...
You get caught using that...
我知道 这次交易没发生过 你并不存在
I know. This never happened. You don't exist.
-很好 -出什么事了吗，伙计?
-Right. -Something wrong , man?
你看起来比平时还苍白
You look a little whiter than usual.
我的电脑，它……
My computer, it...
你有没有过这种感觉
Ever have that feeling,
不知道自己是醒着还是在梦中
where you're not sure if you're awake or still dreaming?
一直都是这样 这叫嗑嗨了
All the time. It's called mescaline.
只有这样才能放飞自我
It's the only way to fly.
听起来你需要休息（双关：拔下插头），伙计
It just sounds like you need to unplug, man.
好好放松一下？
Get some R and R?
你怎么想的，Dujour？ 要不要带他一起去？
What do you think, Dujour? Should we take him with us?
肯定要
Definitely.
不，我去不了 我明天还要上班
No, I can't. I have work tomorrow.
来吧
Come on.
会很有趣的 我保证
It'll be fun. I promise.
好吧
Yeah.
好吧，我去
Sure. I'll go.
你好，尼奥
Hello, Neo.
你怎么知道这个名字的？
How do you know that name?
我知道很多关于你的事情
I know a lot about you.
-你是谁？ -我叫崔尼蒂
-Who are you? -My name is Trinity.
（Trinity 即“三位一体”）
崔尼蒂
Trinity.
那个崔尼蒂？
The Trinity?
入侵国税局数据库的那个崔尼蒂？
That cracked the IRS D-base?
那是很久之前的事了
That was a long time ago.
-上帝啊 -怎么？
-Jesus. -What?
我本以为……
I just thought...
你是个男的
...you were a guy.
多数男人都这么想的
Most guys do.
是你在我的电脑上发消息
That was you on my computer.
你怎么做到的？
How did you do that?
现在，我能告诉你的只有……
Right now, all I can tell you...
你有危险了
...is that you're in danger.
-我带你来是想警告你 -警告什么？
-I brought you here to warn you. -Of what?
他们在监视你，尼奥
They're watching you , Neo.
-谁？ -请听我说
-Who is? -Please just listen.
我知道你为什么来这儿，尼奥
I know why you're here, Neo.
我知道你做了些什么
I know what you've been doing.
我知道为什么你难以入睡
I know why you hardly sleep...
为什么你一个人生活，以及为什么每个夜晚……
...why you live alone and why, night after night...
你都要坐在电脑前
...you sit at your computer.
你是在找他
You're looking for him.
我知道，是因为我也曾寻找他
I know, because I was once looking for the same thing.
当他找到我的时候……
And when he found me...
他告诉我，我其实不是在找他……
...he told me I wasn't really looking for him...
我是在寻找答案
...I was looking for an answer.
是那个问题驱使着我们，尼奥
It's the question that drives us, Neo.
是那个问题让你来到这里
It's the question that brought you here.
你知道问题是什么……
You know the question...
和我一样
...just as I did.
矩阵是什么？
What is the Matrix?
答案近在眼前，尼奥
The answer is out there, Neo.
它也在寻找你
It's looking for you.
它会找到你……
And it will find you...
如果你愿意
...if you want it to.
该死
Shit.
Shit, shit.
（Metacortex公司，meta+cortex，即 超越大脑皮层）
你不喜欢服从权威，安德森先生
You have a problem with authority, Mr. Anderson.
你认为自己很特殊，可以不受规矩的约束
You believe that you are special, that the rules do not apply to you.
很显然，你错了
Obviously, you are mistaken.
这是一个领跑全球的软件公司……
This is one of the top software companies in the world...
是因为每个员工都明白自己是整体的一部分
...because employees understand they are part of a whole.
因此，一个员工出了问题， 就意味着公司出了问题
Thus, if an employee has a problem, the company has a problem.
你该做出选择了，安德森先生
The time has come to make a choice, Mr. Anderson.
要么准时出现在办公桌前，从今天开始
Either you choose to be at your desk on time from this day forth...
要么就另谋高就
...or you choose to find yourself another job.
我讲清楚了吗？
Do I make myself clear?
是的，Mr. Rhineheart 非常清楚了
Yes, Mr. Rhineheart. Perfectly clear.
托马斯·安德森？
Thomas Anderson?
是的，我就是
Yeah , that's me.
Okay.
好的
Great.
祝你度过愉快的一天
Have a nice day.
Hello?
你好，尼奥 你知道我是谁吗？
Hello, Neo. Do you know who this is?
-墨菲斯 -是的
-Morpheus. -Yes.
我一直在找你，尼奥
I've been looking for you, Neo.
我想给你看些东西，我不知道你有没有准备好
I don 't know if you're ready to see what I want to show you.
但很不幸，我们已经没有时间了
But unfortunately, you and I have run out of time.
他们来找你了，尼奥 我不知道他们会对你做什么
They're coming for you, Neo. And l don't know what they're going to do.
谁来找我？
Who's coming for me?
站起来，自己看吧
Stand up and see for yourself.
什么？是现在吗？
What? Right now?
是的 现在
Yes. Now.
慢慢站起来
Do it slowly.
电梯旁
The elevator.
-哦，糟糕！ -是的
-Oh , shit! -Yes.
他们到底想要什么？
What the hell do they want from me?
我不知道 但是要是你也不想知道，就赶快走
I don 't know. But if you don 't want to find out, I suggest you get out of there.
怎么做？
How?
我可以指导你，但是你必须严格按照我说的去做
I can guide you, but you must do exactly as l say.
-好吧 -你对面的隔间是空着的
-Okay. -The cubicle across from you is empty.
-但如果他们…… -快去 现在！
-But what if they…… -Go. Now.
在这儿等一会儿
Stay here for just a moment.
等我告诉你去做的时候，走到这排的尽头……
When l tell you, go to the end of the row...
……到角落那间办公室里
...to the office at the end of the hall.
身体尽量压低
Stay as low as you can.
去吧 现在
Go. Now.
很好 现在，外面有一个吊篮
Good. Now, outside there is a scaffold.
-你怎么知道的？ -我们没时间了，尼奥
-How do you know this? -We don't have time, Neo.
你的左边有一个窗户 过去
To your left there 's a window. Go to it.
打开窗户
Open it.
你要用吊篮上到楼顶
You can use the scaffold to get to the roof.
不行 不行！ 你疯了吗！
No way! No way! This is crazy!
只有两种方法离开这栋建筑
There are two ways out of this building.
要么用吊篮 要么被他们押出去
One is that scaffold. The other is in their custody.
你要走哪条路，自己选吧
You take a chance either way. l leave it to you.
这太疯狂了！
This is insane!
为什么会发生在我身上？
Why is this happening to me?
我都做了些什么？
What'd I do?
我只是个小人物 我什么都没做
I'm nobody. I didn't do anything.
我会死的
I'm gonna die.
该死！
Shit!
糟糕！
Oh, shit!
我不可能做到的
I can't do this.
该死
Shit.
正如你所见，我们关注你有段时间了，安德森先生
As you can see, we've had our eye on you for some time now, Mr. Anderson.
看起来你过着……
It seems that you've been living...
两种生活
...two lives.
第一种生活中，你叫托马斯·A·安德森……
In one life, you're Thomas A. Anderson...
是知名软件公司的程序员
...program writer for a respectable software company.
你有社会保障码 你依法缴税
You have a social security number. You pay your taxes.
而且你还……
And you...
会帮房东太太倒垃圾
...help your landlady carry out her garbage.
另一种是电脑里的生活……
The other life is lived in computers...
在那里你是个化名为“尼奥”的黑客
...where you go by the hacker alias "Neo"...
跟电脑相关的法律，你差不多违反了个遍
...and are guilty of virtually every computer crime we have a law for.
这两种生活中的一种……
One of these lives...
是有未来的
...has a future.
另一种则没有
And one of them does not.
我尽可能说的直白些，安德森先生
I'm going to be as forthcoming as I can be, Mr. Anderson.
请你来这儿……
You're here...
是因为我们需要你的帮助
...because we need your help.
我们知道……
We know that you've been contacted by a certain...
有一个人联系过你
...individual.
一个自称是”墨菲斯“的男子
A man who calls himself "Morpheus."
你怎么看待这个人无关紧要
Whatever you think you know about this man is irrelevant.
但他被各个权威机构认为是……
He is considered by many authorities...
当今最危险的人
...to be the most dangerous man alive.
我的同事们……
My colleagues...
相信我是在跟你白费功夫
...believe that I am wasting my time with you.
但我却相信你想要做正确的事
But I believe you wish to do the right thing.
我们愿意把旧账一笔勾销……
We're willing to wipe the slate clean...
让你重新开始
...give you a fresh start.
我们要的只是你的合作……
All we're asking in return is your cooperation...
将这个臭名昭著的恐怖分子绳之以法
...in bringing a known terrorist to justice.
好吧
Yeah.
这交易听上去真不错
That sounds like a really good deal.
但我有更好的
But I think I got a better one.
要不……
How about...
我给你竖个中指……
...I give you the finger...
你让我打个电话
...and you give me my phone call.
安德森先生……
Umm, Mr. Anderson...
你太让我失望了
...you disappoint me.
别想用盖世太保那套鬼话吓唬我
You can't scare me with this gestapo crap.
我知道自己的权利
I know my rights.
我现在要打个电话
I want my phone call.
告诉我，安德森先生……
Tell me, Mr. Anderson...
打电话还有什么用……
...what good is a phone call...
如果让你话都说不出来？
...if you're unable to speak?
你会帮我们的，安德森先生
You're going to help us, Mr. Anderson...
不管你愿不愿意
...whether you want to or not.
电话线被监听了，所以我长话短说
This line is tapped, so l must be brief.
他们先找到你了，但是他们不知道你有多重要
They got to you first, but they've underestimated how important you are.
如果他们知道我所知道的事……
If they knew what l know...
你恐怕已经死了
...you would probably be dead.
你在说什么？我怎么了？
What are you talking about? What is happening to me?
你是救世主，尼奥 你看，你可能这些年都在找我……
You are the One, Neo. You see, you may have spent the last few years...
但是我花了一辈子……
...looking for me, but l've spent my entire life...
来找你
...looking for you.
你现在还想来见我吗？
Now, do you still want to meet?
-是的 -那就去Adams街的桥下
-Yes. -Then go to the Adams Street bridge.
进来
Get in.
这是干什么？
What the hell is this?
这是必要的手段，尼奥 为了我们的安全
It's necessary, Neo. For our protection.
-谁会伤害你们？ -你
-From what? -From you.
-脱掉上衣 -什么？
-Take off your shirt. -What?
停车
Stop the car.
听好了，白痴
Listen to me, coppertop.
我们没空听你问东问西
（双关：20 Questions 整个三部曲尼奥刚好问了20个问题）
We don't have time for 20 Questions.
现在，只有一条规矩
Right now, there's only one rule:
听我们的……
Our way...
要不就去高速公路（滚下车）
...or the highway.
那好吧
Fine.
求你了，尼奥，你得相信我
Please, Neo, you have to trust me.
-为什么？ -因为你已经来过这里，尼奥
-Why? -Because you have been down there, Neo.
你走过这条路
You know that road.
你非常清楚路的尽头是什么
You know exactly where it ends.
而我知道你不想去那儿
And I know that's not where you want to be.
艾波克，开灯
Apoc, lights.
躺下 上衣掀起来
Lie back. Lift up your shirt.
-这是什么？ -你被窃听了
-What's that? -I think you're bugged.
努力放松
Try and relax.
快点
Come on.
快来吧
它在动了
It's on the move.
快点，混蛋
Come on, you shit.
-你会让它跑掉的 -我不会的
-You're gonna lose it. -No, I'm not.
看到了！
Clear!
上帝啊！ 那东西是真的！？
Jesus Christ! That thing's real!?
这儿就是了
This is it.
我来给你一条建议
Let me give you one piece of advice.
要诚实
Be honest.
他所知道的东西远超你的想象
He knows more than you can imagine.
终于
At last.
欢迎你，尼奥
Welcome, Neo.
你无疑已经猜到……
As you no doubt have guessed...
我就是墨菲斯
...I am Morpheus.
很荣幸见到你
It's an honor to meet you.
不
No...
这是我的荣幸
...the honor is mine.
请这边坐
Please, come. Sit down.
我猜
I imagine...
你现在感觉有点像爱丽丝
...that right now you're feeling a bit like Alice...
跌进了兔子洞？
...tumbling down the rabbit hole?
可以这么说
You could say that.
我能从你眼中看出来
I can see it in your eyes.
为了从梦中醒来……
You have the look of a man who accepts what he sees...
你会相信亲眼所见的一切
...because he's expecting to wake up.
讽刺的是，这离事实不远了
Ironically, this is not far from the truth.
你相信命运吗，尼奥？
Do you believe in fate, Neo?
不信
No.
为什么不？
Why not?
因为我不喜欢对自己的生活失去控制
Because I don't like the idea that I'm not in control of my life.
我完全明白你的意思
I know exactly what you mean.
我来告诉你你为什么会来到这里吧
Let me tell you why you're here.
因为你知道了一些东西
You are here because you know something.
这些东西，你自己也无法解释
What you know, you can't explain.
但你就是能感觉到
But you feel it.
你这一生都感觉得到：
You felt it your entire life:
这个世界有些异样 你不知道是什么，但就是觉得不对
That there's something wrong with the world. You don't know what, but it's there.
如同扎在心头的一根刺……
Like a splinter in your mind...
快要把你逼疯
...driving you mad.
正是这种感受把你带到了我面前
It is this feeling that has brought you to me.
你明白我在说什么吗？
Do you know what I'm talking about?
矩阵？
The Matrix?
你 想要 知道
Do you want to know...
它究竟是什么吗？
...what it is?
矩阵无处不在
The Matrix is everywhere.
它就在我们身边
It is all around us.
甚至此时此刻，它就在这间屋子里
Even now, in this very room.
当你看向窗外……
You can see it when you look out your window...
或者打开电视，都能看到它
...or when you turn on your television.
无论是你上班的时候……
You can feel it when you go to work...
去教堂的时候……
...when you go to church...
还是缴税的时候，都可以感觉到它的存在
...when you pay your taxes.
它就是这个充斥了你的视野的世界……
It is the world that has been pulled over your eyes...
阻挡你看见真相
...to blind you from the truth.
什么真相？
What truth?
你是个奴隶，尼奥
That you are a slave, Neo.
和所有人一样，你生在囹圄之中
Like everyone else, you were born into bondage...
生在一座囚禁了你所有感官的监狱中里
...born into a prison that you cannot smell or taste or touch.
一座……
A prison...
囚禁你的意识的监狱
...for your mind.
不幸的是，没有人可以……
Unfortunately, no one can be...
被告知矩阵究竟是什么
...told what the Matrix is.
除非让你亲眼得见
You have to see it for yourself.
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance.
一旦做出选择，再无回头之路
After this, there is no turning back.
吃下蓝药丸……
You take the blue pill...
故事到此为止，你会在床上醒来并继续相信……
...the story ends, you wake up in your bed and believe...
你愿意相信的一切
...whatever you want to believe.
吃下红药丸……
You take the red pill...
你将继续漫游奇境
...you stay in Wonderland...
我会将想你展示这兔子洞有多深
...and I show you how deep the rabbit hole goes.
切记……
Remember...
我向你展示的只有真相 没有别的
...all I'm offering is the truth. Nothing more.
跟我来
Follow me.
艾波克，我们接上线路了吗？
Apoc, are we on-line?
快了
Almost.
时间总是对我们不够用
Time is always against us.
请坐在这儿
Please, take a seat there.
-你也经历过这一切？ -对啊
-You did all this? -Mm-hm.
你服下的药丸是追踪程序的一部分
The pill you took is part of a trace program.
作用是干扰你的输入输出载波信号，好让我们给你定位
It's designed to disrupt your input/outout carrier signals, so we can pinpoint your location.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思是系好安全带，小妞（多萝西）
It means buckle your seat belt, Dorothy...
跟你的老家（堪萨斯州）
...because Kansas...
说拜拜吧
...is going bye-bye.
你看到了吗？
Did you...?
你可曾做过这样的梦，尼奥 一个让你无比相信那就是真实的梦？
Have you ever had a dream , Neo, that you were so sure was real?
如果你无法从那个梦中醒来，该怎么办？
What if you were unable to wake from that dream?
你又该如何区分梦境……
How would you know the difference between the dream world...
和现实世界？
...and the real world?
这不可能
This can't be.
什么不可能？
Be what?
不可能是真的？
Be real?
-开始复制信号 -艾波克？
-It's going into replication. -Apoc?
还是没找到
Still nothing.
冷
It's cold.
好冷！
It's cold!
坦克，尽快发信号过来
Tank, we're going to need a signal soon.
-检测到房颤 -艾波克，定位信息
-I got a fibrillation. -Apoc, location.
马上定位到目标了
Targeting almost there.
他的心跳要停止了
He's going into arrest.
-锁定 我找到他了 -坦克，就现在！
-Lock. I got him! -Now, Tank, now!
欢迎……
Welcome...
来到真实的世界
...to the real world.
我们做到了，崔尼蒂
We've done it, Trinity.
我们找到了他
We found him.
-希望你是对的 -我不用“希望”
-I hope you're right. -I don't have to hope.
我“相信”
I know it.
我是死了吗？
Am I dead?
早着呢
Far from it.
他还需要很长时间的恢复
He still needs a lot of work.
你们在做什么？
What are you doing?
你的肌肉萎缩了 我们在帮你重生肌肉
Your muscles atrophied. We're rebuilding them.
我的眼睛怎么这么疼？
Why do my eyes hurt?
因为你从未睁开过双眼
You've never used them before.
休息吧，尼奥
Rest, Neo.
你就快知道答案了
The answers are coming.
墨菲斯，我怎么了？
Morpheus, what's happened to me?
这是哪里？
What is this place?
你更应该问现在是“什么时候”了
More important than "what" is "when."
“什么时候”？
"When"?
你以为现在是1999年……
You believe it's the year 1999...
其实是更接近2199年
...when in fact, it's closer to 2199.
我没法告诉你具体是哪一年……
I can't tell you exactly what year it is...
因为说实话我也不知道
...because we honestly don't know.
我无法用语言向你解释，尼奥
There's nothing I can say that will explain it for you.
跟我来 亲眼来看看吧
Come with me. See for yourself.
这就是我的战舰
This is my ship.
（来自圣经《但以理书》，尼布甲尼撒二世为其妻建造了巴比伦的空中花园）
尼布甲尼撒号 是一艘气垫船
The Nebuchadnezzar. It's a hovercraft.
这是主甲板
This is the main deck.
这里是控制中枢
This is the core...
我们在这里广播非法信号黑进矩阵
...where we broadcast our pirate signal and hack into the Matrix.
大多数船员你都认识了
Most of my crew you already know.
这是艾波克
This is Apoc...
斯维奇
...Switch...
-还有塞弗
-...and Cypher. -Hi.
你没见过的是坦克和他哥哥多泽
The ones you don't know: Tank and his big brother, Dozer.
你身后的小家伙是耗子
The little one behind you is Mouse.
你想见识矩阵是什么吗，尼奥？
You wanted to know what the Matrix is, Neo?
Trinity.
试着放轻松
Try to relax.
你会感觉有点怪异
This will feel a little weird.
这里……
This...
就是主架构
...is the Construct.
这是我们的载入程序
It's our loading program.
我们可以载入任何东西，从衣服……
We can load anything, from clothing...
到装备……
...to equipment...
武器
...weapons...
仿真训练
...training simulations...
我们需要的任何东西
...anything we need.
现在我们是在计算机程序里？
Right now we're inside a computer program?
真的如此难以接受吗？
Is it really so hard to believe?
你穿的衣服变了 手臂上和脑后的接口也没了
Your clothes are different. The plugs in your arms and head are gone.
你的发型也变了
Your hair has changed.
你现在的外貌叫做"自我形象残留"
Your appearance now is what we call "residual self-image."
它是你数字自我的心理映射
It is the mental projection of your digital self.
这不是真的？
This isn't real?
什么是“真实”？
What is "real"?
如何去定义“真实”？
How do you define "real"?
如果你指的是可被感知到的事物……
If you're talking about what you can feel...
可以被闻到，被尝到，被看到的……
...what you can smell , taste and see...
那所谓的“真实”就无非是大脑里处理的电信号
...then "real" is simply electrical signals interpreted by your brain.
这是你所熟悉的那个世界
This, is the world that you know.
这个世界处在20世纪末的样子
The world as it was at the end of the 20th century.
现在它只存在于神经网络交互模拟系统中，成为了它的一部分
It exists now only as part of a neural-interactive simulation...
它被我们称为矩阵
...that we call the Matrix.
你一直生活在梦境中，尼奥
You've been living in a dream world , Neo.
这才是世界……
This is the world...
现实的模样
...as it exists today.
欢迎来到……
Welcome to "the desert...
“真实的荒漠”
...of the real."
我们只掌握了残缺不全的资料
We have only bits and pieces of information.
但我们确知的是，在21世纪初的某个时刻……
But what we know for certain is that at some point in the early 21st century,
人类普天同庆
...all of mankind was united in celebration.
我们惊叹于自己的伟大成就，也就是AI的诞生
We marveled at our own magnificence as we gave birth to A.I.
A.I.
你是指人工智能
You mean artificial intelligence.
一种非凡的的意识催生了整个机器种族。
A singular consciousness that spawned an entire race of machines.
究竟是我们还是它们率先进攻已不得而知
We don't know who struck first, us or them.
不过是我们熏黑了天空
But we know that it was us that scorched the sky.
当时，机器人十分依赖太阳能
At the time, they were dependent on solar power,
而人类相信它们将无法存活……
...and it was believed that they would be unable to survive...
如果失去了像太阳这样充足的能量来源
...without an energy source as abundant as the sun.
纵观人类历史，我们的生存一度是那么依赖机器
Throughout human history, we have been dependent on machines to survive.
命运，看起来就是这么讽刺
Fate, it seems, is not without a sense of irony.
人体产生的生物电，比一节120伏的电池还多
The human body generates more bioelectricity than a 120-volt battery.
还有产生的超过25000BTU的生物热
And over 25,000 BTUs of body heat.
再结合核聚变的方式……
Combined with a form of fusion...
机器得到了所需的全部能源
...the machines had found all the energy they would ever need.
这里有养殖场，尼奥，望不到边的牧场
There are fields, Neo, endless fields...
在那里人类不再是被生出来的
...where human beings are no longer born.
而是被种植出来的
We are grown.
很长一段时间里，我并不相信这个
For the longest time, I wouldn't believe it.
直到我亲眼看见发电厂……
And then I saw the fields with my own eyes...
看它们将死者液化
...watched them liquefy the dead...
以便静脉注射饲喂给活人
...so they could be fed intravenously to the living.
我站在那儿，面对着这种纯粹的恐怖的精细
And standing there, facing the pure, horrifying precision...
我终于意识到事实就摆在眼前
...I came to realize the obviousness of the truth.
矩阵本质上是什么？
What is the Matrix?
是控制
Control.
矩阵就是电脑生成的梦境世界
The Matrix is a computer-generated dream world...
用来控制我们
...built to keep us under control...
为了把人类……
...in order to change a human being...
变成电池
...into this.
不！
No.
我不信
I don't believe it.
这不可能
It's not possible.
我没说过这很容易接受，尼奥 但我说过，这就是真相
I didn't say it would be easy, Neo. I just said it would be the truth.
快停下！
Stop!
让我出去！
Let me out!
放我出去！ 我要出去！
Let me out! I want out!
-放松，尼奥 放松 -把这玩意拔下来
-Easy, Neo. Easy. -Get this thing out of me.
快给我拔下来！
Get this thing out of me!
别碰我！
Don't touch me!
别过来！
Stay away from me!
我不信
I don't believe it.
-他要跪 -呼吸，尼奥
-He's gonna pop. -Breathe, Neo.
深呼吸
Just breathe.
我不能回头了，是不是？
I can't go back, can I?
不能
No.
就算你能回去……
But if you could...
你真的愿意这么做吗？
...would you really want to?
我觉得应该向你道歉
I feel I owe you an apology.
我们有个规矩
We have a rule.
我们不能解救达到一定年龄限制的意识
We never free a mind once it's reached a certain age.
这很危险
It's dangerous.
他们不能放下
The mind has trouble letting go.
我见过这样的事，我很抱歉
I've seen it before, and I'm sorry.
我这么做也是因为……
I did what I did because...
迫不得已
...I had to.
矩阵建立之初，里面诞生了一个人……
When the Matrix was first built, there was a man born inside...
他能够随心所欲地……
...who had the ability to change whatever he wanted...
更改矩阵
...to remake the Matrix as he saw fit.
就是他解放了我们的先民……
It was he who freed the first of us...
教导我们真相
...taught us the truth.
只要矩阵还存在……
As long as the Matrix exists...
人类就永不得解脱
...the human race will never be free.
他死后……
After he died...
先知预言他将再临
...the Oracle prophesied his return...
他的到来将会彻底摧毁矩阵
...and that his coming would hail the destruction of the Matrix...
结束这场战争
...end the war...
为我们的子民带来自由
...bring freedom to our people.
这就是为什么像我这样的人要终其一生在矩阵中搜索……
That is why there are those of us who spent our lives searching the Matrix...
寻找救世主
...looking for him.
我这么做是因为……
I did what I did because...
我相信我终于找到了
...I believe that search is over.
休息一下吧
Get some rest.
你会用得着的
You're going to need it.
为了什么？
For what?
你的训练
Your training.
早上好 昨晚睡着了吗？
Morning. Did you sleep?
今晚你就睡得着了
You will tonight.
我保证
I guarantee it.
我叫坦克 你的接线员
I'm Tank. I'll be your operator.
-你身上怎么没有…… -插孔吗？没有
-You don't, you don't have any- Holes? Nope.
我和我哥多泽都是，百分百存粹的用古老的方生孕育的人类
Me and my brother, Dozer, are both 100% pure, old-fashioned, homegrown human.
生而自由
Born free right here...
生在真实的世界中
...in the real world.
是真正的锡安的孩子
Genuine child of Zion.
-锡安？ -如果明天战争就会结束……
-Zion? -If the war was over tomorrow...
锡安会欢庆的
...Zion's where the party would be.
它是座城市？
It's a city?
最后的人类城市 我们仅存的居住地
The last human city. The only place we have left.
它在哪？
Where is it?
深入地下，接近地核，那里比较暖和
Deep underground near the Earth's core, where it's still warm.
如果你命硬 没准还能亲眼看见呢
You live long enough, you might see it.
天生的！ 我得告诉你，我真想见识下你的本事……
Goddamn! I gotta tell you, I'm excited to see what you're capable of...
如果墨菲斯是对的
...if Morpheus is right and all.
本来我不该说这个，但是……
We're not supposed to talk about this, but...
如果你真的是……
...if you are...
那就太棒了
...it's a very exciting time.
我们有很多事情要做 我们得开始了
We got a lot to do. We gotta get to it.
按理说，我们得先从这些操作程序学起
We're supposed to start with these operation programs first.
这是最无聊的 让我们来点带劲的
That's major boring shit. Let's do something more fun.
不如就来……
How about...
格斗训练吧？
...combat training?
柔道？
"Jujitsu"?
我要学柔道？
I'm going to learn jujitsu?
我去！
Holy shit!
"嗨，小麦 我觉得他喜欢"（麦片广告语）
"Hey, Mikey, I think he likes it."
还要再来一点吗？
How about some more?
要
Hell, yes.
当然要
Hell, yeah.
他怎么样了？
How is he?
连着学了十个小时 简直是台机器
Ten hours straight. He's a machine.
我会功夫了
I know kung fu.
给我露一手
Show me.
这是一个陪练程序
This is a sparring program...
与矩阵中编写的现实情况相似
...similar to the programmed reality of the Matrix.
有着相同的基本规则 比如重力
It has the same basic rules. Like gravity.
你必须清楚这些规则和计算机系统里的别无二致
What you must learn is that these rules are no different than those of a computer system.
有些则可以变通
Some of them can be bent.
另一些甚至可以打破
Others can be broken.
明白了吗？
Understand?
那么来打我吧……
Then hit me...
如果你有本事做到
...if you can.
很好！
Good !
适应能力
Adaptation.
随机应变
Improvisation.
但你的弱点
But your weakness...
并不于招式技巧
...is not your technique.
墨菲斯和尼奥打起来了
Morpheus is fighting Neo.
我是怎么击败你的？
How did I beat you?
你太快了
You're too fast.
你是相信……
Do you believe that...
我的更强更快
...my being stronger or faster...
在这里与我的肌肉有关系吗？
...has anything to do with my muscles in this place?
你觉得现在呼吸的是空气吗？
You think that's air you're breathing now?
再来！
Again!
上帝啊，他真快！
Jesus Christ, he's fast!
瞧他的神经元活动，远超常人了
Take a look at his neuro-kinetics, they are way above normal.
你还在等什么？
What are you waiting for?
你能做到的远比这个快
You're faster than this.
不要光去想
Don't think you are.
要相信你可以
Know you are.
来呀！别老试着打我，要真的做出来
Come on! Stop trying to hit me, and hit me!
难以置信
I don't believe it.
我明白你是想做什么了
I know what you're trying to do.
我想解放你的意识，尼奥
I'm trying to free your mind , Neo.
但我只能将你领到门口
But I can only show you the door.
你只能自己走进去
You are the one that has to walk through it.
坦克，载入跳跃程序
Tank, load the jump program.
你必须放下，尼奥 恐惧……
You have to let it all go, Neo. Fear...
犹疑和不自信
...doubt and disbelief.
解放 你的 意识
Free your mind.
Whoa.
好吧 好吧
Okey-dokey.
解放我的意识
Free my mind.
要是他成功了呢？
What if he makes it?
-第一次没人能跳过去 -我知道
-No one's ever made their first jump. -I know, I know.
-但如果他跳过去了呢 -不会的
-But what if he does? -He won't.
加油
Come on.
好吧
All right.
没问题的 解放我的意识
No problem. Free my mind.
解放我的意识 没问题的 好的
Free my mind. No problem. Right.
这是什么意思？
What does that mean?
没什么意思
It doesn't mean anything.
每个人第一次都会摔下去
Everybody falls the first time.
对吧，崔尼蒂？
Right, Trin?
-程序不是虚拟的吗 -你的大脑以为它成了真
-I thought it wasn't real. -Your mind makes it real.
如果在矩阵中被杀……
If you're killed in the Matrix...
就真的死了吗
...you die here?
没有了意识，身体没法存活
The body cannot live without the mind.
我都不记得你哪次给我送过晚饭
I don't remember you ever bringing me dinner.
他有些特别，不是吗？
There is something about him, isn't there?
你不会也信预言了吧？
Don't tell me you're a believer now?
我只是好奇……
I keep wondering...
如果墨菲斯这么确定，为何不带他去见先知呢？
...if Morpheus is so sure, why not take him to see the Oracle?
等他准备好了墨菲斯自然会去的
Morpheus will take him when he's ready.
矩阵是一个系统，尼奥
The Matrix is a system, Neo.
这个系统是我们的敌人
That system is our enemy.
但是在里面的时候，你看看四周，发现什么？
But when you're inside, you look around what do you see?
商人 教师 律师 木匠
Businessmen , teachers, lawyers, carpenters.
是我们亟待拯救的一个个意识
The very minds of the people we are trying to save.
但那之前，他们还是系统的一部分……
But until we do, these people are a part of that system...
这意味着他们还是我们的敌人
...and that makes them our enemy.
你得明白……
You have to understand...
大多数人都没准备好被拔掉插头
...most of these people are not ready to be unplugged.
许多人惰性太强……
And many of them are so inert...
如此无助地依赖着这个系统……
...so hopelessly dependent on the system...
他们甚至会奋力保护它
...that they will fight to protect it.
你是在听我说话呢，尼奥？ 还是在看那个红衣女郎？
Were you listening to me, Neo? Or were you looking at the woman in the red dress?
-我在…… -再回头看看
-I was... -Look again.
定格
Freeze it.
-这不是在矩阵中吗？ -不
-This isn't the Matrix? -No.
这也是个训练程序，为了让你明白一件事：
It's another training program designed to teach you one thing:
不属于我们的，就是敌人
If you are not one of us, you are one of them.
-他们是谁？ -监测程序
-What are they? -Sentient programs.
他们能自由出入任何通过物理接口连上机器系统的软件
They can move in and out of any software still hardwired to their system.
也就是说任何没有拔掉插头的人
That means that anyone we haven't unplugged...
都是潜在的特工
...is potentially an agent.
在矩阵中……
Inside the Matrix...
他们可以是任何人……
...they are everyone...
却又不是任何人
...and they are no one.
碰到他们，我们可以靠躲藏或逃跑来逃过一劫
We have survived by hiding and running from them...
但他们也是守门人
...but they are the gatekeepers.
把守着每一个出入口，保管着所有的钥匙
They're guarding all the doors and holding all the keys.
也就是说 总有一天有人得挑战他们
Which means that sooner or later, someone will have to fight them.
有人？
Someone?
我不想骗你，尼奥
I won't lie to you , Neo.
每个不肯屈服的男人或女人，每一个挑战特工的人都已经死了
Every single man or woman who has stood their ground, everyone who has fought an agent has died.
但他们做不到的，你会做到的
But where they have failed, you will succeed.
为什么？
Why?
我见过特工一拳打穿混凝土墙
I've seen an agent punch through a concrete wall.
整支弹匣打空也伤不到他们
Men have emptied entire clips at them and hit nothing but air.
可他们的力量与速度，仍然局限在矩阵的规则内
Yet their strength and speed are still based in a world built on rules.
因此……
Because of that...
他们永远不可能和你一样的强大和迅速
...they will never be as strong or as fast as you can be.
你是想告诉我什么？
What are you telling me?
是告诉我我能躲子弹？
That I can dodge bullets?
不，尼奥
No, Neo.
我是说，当你准备好了……
I'm trying to tell you that when you're ready...
你根本不必躲
...you won't have to.
我们有麻烦了
We got trouble.
-是锡安发来的警告吗？ -不，另一艘战舰发的
-Did Zion send the warning? -No, another ship.
该死
Shit.
-乌贼扫荡得真快 -乌贼？
-Squiddy's sweeping in quick. -Squiddy?
就是哨兵 专为一项任务设计的杀戮机器
A sentinel. A killing machine designed for one thing.
搜寻并清除
Search and destroy.
就把船停在那里
Set her down right over there.
情况怎么样，坦克？
How are we doing, Tank?
关闭电源
Power off-line.
EMP 充能……
EMP armed...
-就绪了 -EMP？
-...and ready. -EMP?
电磁脉冲武器
Electromagnetic pulse.
能使爆炸范围内的所有电子系统瘫痪
Disables any electrical system in the blast radius.
是我们对抗机器的唯一武器
It's the only weapon we have against the machines.
-我们在哪？ -废弃的给排水系统里
-Where are we? -Their old service and waste systems.
下水管道
Sewers.
上面原来有方圆百里的城市
There used to be cities that spanned hundreds of miles.
现在就只剩下水管路了
Now these sewers are all that's Ieft.
安静
Quiet.
哇哦！尼奥
Whoa! Neo.
你把我吓得个半死
You scared the bejesus out of me.
-对不起 -算了
-Sorry. -It's okay.
这是……
Is that...?
矩阵吗？
The Matrix?
是啊
Yeah.
-你查看的一直是它的代码吗? -是呀，必须这样
-Do you always look at it encoded? -Well, you have to.
构建程序的时候才用到图像转换器
The image translators work for the construct program.
但矩阵的信息量太大了，没法完全解码
But there's way too much information to decode the Matrix.
你得习惯这么做 在我眼里这些不再是代码
You get used to it. I don't even see the code.
而是金棕头发、黑头发，红头发的人
All I see is blonde, brunette, redhead.
你想……
Do you...
喝一杯吗？
...want a drink?
可以
Sure.
要知道……
You know...
我明白你在想什么
...I know what you're thinking.
因为此时此刻我也想着同样的事
Because right now I'm thinking the same thing.
事实上，自从我来这儿就从没断过这样的念头
Actually, I've been thinking it ever since I got here.
为什么啊，为什么我当初不选蓝药丸呢?
Why, oh, why didn't I take the blue pill?
活像喝尿，哈？
Good shit, huh?
多泽酿的
Dozer makes it.
它只有两点用处：
It's good for two things:
引擎祛油和杀脑细胞
Degreasing engines and killing brain cells.
嗯我能问你个问题吗？
So can I ask you something?
墨菲斯告诉你为什么要这么做了吗？
Did he tell you why he did it?
为什么你会来到这儿？
Why you're here?
上帝啊！
Jesus!
他这洗脑工作做的真好
What a mind job.
这么说，你来这儿是为了拯救世界
So you're here to save the world.
对此，我还能说啥好呢？
What do you say to something like that?
只能给个小小的建议吧
A little piece of advice.
一看到特工……
You see an agent...
你还是像我们一样：
...you do what we do:
拔腿就跑吧
Run.
没命地逃啊
You run your ass off.
谢谢你的饮料
Thanks for the drink.
做个好梦
Sweet dreams.
我们谈妥了吗，里根先生？
Do we have a deal, Mr. Reagan?
要知道……
You know...
我知道这块牛排并不存在
...I know this steak doesn't exist.
我知道当我把它送入嘴里……
I know that when I put it in my mouth...
矩阵会告诉我的大脑……
...the Matrix is telling my brain that it is...
它多汁……
...juicy...
又可口
...and delicious.
过了九年了……
After nine years...
知道我终于想明白了什么吗？
...you know what I realize?
无知是福
Ignorance is bliss.
那么我们就说定了
Then we have a deal.
我什么也不想记得
I don't want to remember nothing.
忘掉一切 明白吗？
Nothing. You understand?
我还要变得富有
And I want to be rich.
做个有头有脸的人物
You know, someone important.
比如当个演员
Like an actor.
想要什么都可以，里根先生
Whatever you want, Mr. Reagan.
Okay.
把我的身体运回发电厂
You get my body back in a power plant...
重新接入矩阵
...reinsert me into the Matrix...
我就给你想要的东西
...I'II get you what you want.
锡安主机的接入密码
Access codes to the Zion mainframe.
办不到 我告诉过你，我也不知道
No. I told you, I don't know them.
但是我可以给你知道密码的人
I can get you the man who does.
墨菲斯
Morpheus.
给你，伙计 冠军早餐
Here you go, buddy. Breakfast of champions.
闭上眼睛的话，就像是吃软煎蛋
If you close your eyes, it feels like you're eating runny eggs.
更像是一碗鼻涕
Or a bowl of snot.
知道这让我想起来什么吗？
You know what it really reminds me of?
味好美麦片 吃过吗？
Tastee Wheat. Did you ever eat Tastee Wheat?
没有，但从理论上说，你也没有真的吃过
No, but technically, neither did you.
我想说的正是这个 正是！
That's exactly my point. Exactly.
因为你现在想想……
Because you have to wonder, now...
机器又是怎么知道味好美麦片到底是什么味道呢？
...how do the machines really know what Tastee Wheat tasted like, huh?
也许它们搞错了
Maybe they got it wrong.
也许味好美麦片尝起来，实际上像是……
Maybe what I think Tastee Wheat tasted like, actually tasted like...
燕麦粥或者金枪鱼
...oatmeal or tuna fish.
这就让人联想到很多东西 比如说吧，鸡肉
That makes you wonder about a lot of things. You take chicken for example.
也许机器就搞不清楚鸡肉是什么味儿
Maybe they couldn't figure out what to make chicken taste like
所以鸡肉才能有各种味道
...which is why it tastes like everything.
-也许它们可以把你…… -闭嘴吧，耗子
-And maybe they can get you outs... -Shut up, Mouse.
这是一种单细胞蛋白质……
It's a single-celled protein...
混合了人工合成的氨基酸、维生素和矿物质
...combined with synthetic aminos, vitamins and minerals.
包含了身体所需的一切
Everything the body needs.
当然没有包含所需的一切
It doesn't have everything the body needs.
听说你通过了特工训练程序
So I understand that you've run through the agent training program.
知道吗，那程序是我写的
You know, I wrote that program.
又来这套
Here it comes.
-你觉得她怎么样？ -谁？
-So What did you think of her? -Of who?
红衣女郎啊 她是我设计的
The woman in the red dress. I designed her.
她话不多，但要是……
She doesn't talk very much, but...
要是你想见她，我还能安排你们私下幽会呢
...but if you'd like to meet her, I can arrange a more personal milieu.
这数字皮条客干的真起劲呢
The digital pimp hard at work.
别理这些伪君子，尼奥
Pay no attention to these hypocrites, Neo.
否认自己的生理本能……
To deny our own impulses...
就是否认自己的人性
...is to deny the very thing that makes us human.
多泽，吃完之后
Dozer, when you're done...
把船开到可以广播信号的深度
...bring the ship up to broadcast depth.
我们要进矩阵
We're going in.
带尼奥去见她
I'm taking Neo to see her.
见谁？
See who?
先知
The Oracle.
乘客们请注意
Everyone please observe...
"系好安全带"和"请勿吸烟"指示灯已亮
...the "fasten seat belt" and "no smoking" signs are on.
请坐稳 祝大家旅途愉快
Sit back and enjoy your flight.
进来了
We're in.
我们一个小时之后就回来
We'll be back in an hour.
难以置信……
Unbelievable...
不是吗？
...isn't it?
-天呐 -怎么了？
-God! -What?
我在那家店吃过饭
I used to eat there.
面条真是不错
Really good noodles.
我一生中的这么多记忆
I have these memories from my life.
竟都不是真实发生的
None of them happened.
这意味着什么呢？
What does that mean?
矩阵无法告诉你你是谁
That the Matrix cannot tell you who you are.
先知就可以吗？
But an oracle can?
这是两码事
That's different.
你去见过她吗
Did you go to her?
见过
Yes.
她跟你说了些什么？
What did she tell you?
她告诉我……
She told me...
告诉什么？
What?
到地方了
We're here.
尼奥，跟我来
Neo, come with me.
所以这是同一个先知吗，跟那个作出……
So is this the same oracle that made the ...
救世主的预言？
...the prophecy?
是同一个 她很老了 从一开始她就与我们同在
Yes. She's very old. She's been with us since the beginning.
-什么的一开始？ -抵抗运动
-The beginning? -Of the Resistance.
她都知道什么? 任何事情？
And she knows what? Everything?
用她的话说就是“一切需要她知道事”
She would say she knows enough.
而且从未出错？
And she's never wrong.
不要总想着对与错
Try not to think of it in terms of right and wrong.
她只是个指路人，尼奥
She is a guide, Neo.
指引你该走哪条路
She can help you to find the path.
她帮助过你？
She helped you?
没错
Yes.
她对你怎么说？
What did she tell you?
她说我会找到救世主
That I would find the One.
我说过我只能将你领到门口
I told you I can only show you the door.
你得自己走进去
You have to walk through it.
你好，尼奥
Hello, Neo.
你来的正是时候
You're right on time.
请自便，墨菲斯 尼奥，跟我来
Make yourself at home, Morpheus. Neo, come with me.
这些是其他候选人
These are the other Potentials.
你可以在这里等候
You can wait here.
不要想着弄弯勺子
Do not try and bend the spoon.
那是不可能的
That's impossible.
而是要认清这个事实
Instead, only try to realize the truth.
什么事实？
What truth?
根本没有勺子
There is no spoon.
没有勺子？
There is no spoon?
你就会明白：弯曲的不是勺子，而是你自己
Then you'll see that it is not the spoon that bends. It is only yourself.
现在先知可以见你了
The Oracle will you see now.
我知道你叫尼奥
I know you're Neo.
请稍等片刻
Be right with you.
-你就是先知？ -猜对了
-You're the Oracle? -Bingo.
跟你想象的不一样，对吧？
Not quite what you were expecting, right?
就快好了
Almost done.
闻起来很香吧？
Smell good, don't they?
对
Yeah.
我本来是要请你坐下的……
I'd ask you to sit down...
不过反正你也不会坐的
...but you're not going to anyway.
-还有不用担心花瓶的事 -什么花瓶？
-And don't worry about the vase. -What vase?
那个花瓶
That vase.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我说了，没关系的
I said, don't worry about it.
我会让孩子们修好它的
I'll get one of my kids to fix it.
你怎么知道的？
How did you know?
真正会让你苦思冥想的是……
What's really going to bake your noodle later on is...
如果我不去提它，你还会打碎它吗？
...would you still have broken it if I hadn't said anything?
你比我预想的还要可爱
You're cuter than I thought.
我明白她为什么喜欢你了
I can see why she likes you.
谁？
Who?
可惜不怎么聪明
Not too bright, though.
你知道为什么墨菲斯带你来见我
You know why Morpheus brought you to see me.
那么……
So...
你自己怎么想的？
...what do you think?
你觉得自己是救世主吗？
Do you think you are the One?
老实说 我不知道
Honestly I don't know.
知道那几个字是什么意思吗？
You know what that means?
是拉丁文
It's Latin.
意思是，“认识你自己”
Means, "Know thyself."
让我告诉你个小秘密吧
I'll let you in on a little secret.
做救世主就像谈恋爱一样
Being the One is just like being in love.
没人会提醒你陷入爱河了 但你自己就是知道……
No one can tell you you're in love. You just know it...
从头到尾……
...through and through.
刻骨铭心
Balls to bones.
好吧……
Well...
我得好好看看你
...I'd better have a look at you.
张嘴，说“啊~”
Open your mouth. Say, "Ah."
好吧
Okay...
现在我得说“嗯，挺有意思的，不过……”
Now I'm supposed to say, "Hmm , that's interesting , but..."
而你会问：
Then you say:
不过什么？
But what?
不过你已经知道我要说什么了
But you already know what I'm going to tell you.
-我不是救世主 -很遗憾，孩子
-I'm not the One. -Sorry, kid.
你有天分……
You got the gift...
但看起来你在等待什么
...but it looks like you're waiting for something.
在等什么？
What?
等下辈子吧，大概，谁知道呢？
（双关：next life 亦指代死后的新生）
Your next life, maybe. Who knows?
事情总是不尽如人意
That's the way these things go.
-你在笑什么？ -墨菲斯……
-What's funny? -Morpheus.
他几乎让我信以为真了
He almost had me convinced.
我明白
I know.
可怜的墨菲斯
Poor Morpheus.
（Morpheus 一名取自希腊神话的梦神，即“造梦者”）
要是没有他，我们就迷失了
Without him, we're lost.
“要是没有他”，你是指什么？
What do you mean, "without him"?
你真的想听吗？
Are you sure you want to hear this?
墨菲斯相信你，尼奥
Morpheus believes in you, Neo.
没有人，甚至你我都不能……
And no one, not you, not even me...
动摇他的信念
...can convince him otherwise.
他如此盲目地相信你就是救世主……
He believes it so blindly...
以至于愿意牺牲自己拯救你的生命
...that he's going to sacrifice his life to save yours.
什么？
What?
你将不得不做出选择
You're going to have to make a choice.
一边是墨菲斯的性命
In the one hand, you'll have Morpheus' life.
一边是你自己的
And in the other hand, you'll have your own.
你们中的一个会死
One of you is going to die.
至于哪一个，将取决于你
Which one will be up to you.
我很抱歉，孩子 真的
I'm sorry, kiddo. I really am.
你有颗善良的心
You have a good soul.
我最讨厌告诉好人坏消息了
And I hate giving good people bad news.
别担心了
Don't worry about it.
只要你一离开这扇门……
As soon as you step outside that door...
就会感觉好些的
...you'll start feeling better.
你会记起，自己从来不信宿命论这种鬼话
You'll remember you don't believe in any of this fate crap.
你可是说过要掌控自己的人生
You're in control of your own life.
还记得吗？
Remember?
过来……
Here...
拿块曲奇吧
（双关：cookie 亦指互联网中每个用户的特异性身份识别码）
...take a cookie.
我保证，只要一吃下它……
I promise, by the time you're done eating it...
你的心情就和往常一样好了
...you'll feel right as rain.
她说过的话……
What was said...
就是给你的
...was for you...
只说给你一个人听
...and for you alone.
他们在回来的路上了
They're on the way.
那是什么？
What is that?
（Déjà vu 法语 即 "already seen"）
哦 似曾相识
Oh, Déjà vu.
你说什么？
What did you just say?
没什么 就是有点似曾相识
Nothing. Just having a little Déjà vu.
你看见什么了？ 发生什么了？
What did you see? What happened?
刚才有只黑猫走过
A black cat went past us...
然后又过去一只一模一样的
...then another just like it.
有多像？ 是同一只猫吗？
How much like it? Was it the same cat?
-好像是的 我不确定 -斯维奇，艾波克
-Might have been. I'm not sure. -Switch, Apoc.
这是什么？
What is it?
这种似曾相识通常是矩阵被修改时出的小故障
A Déjà vu is usually a glitch in the Matrix when they change something.
上帝啊！
Oh, my God.
我们走
Let's go.
他们把电话线剪断了 是陷阱！ 快跑!
They cut the hard line. It's a trap! Get out!
哦不！
Oh, no.
他们修改了这儿 咱们困在这出不去了
That's what they changed. We're trapped.
冷静！ 把手机给我
Be calm. Give me your phone.
他们会追踪到的
They'll be able to track it.
没别的选择了
We have no choice.
-接线员 -坦克
-Operator. -Tank…
找一下这栋楼的结构图纸 要快！
Find a structural drawing of this building. Find it fast.
-找到了！ -主管道墙在哪
-Got it! -l need the main wet-wall.
在八楼
Eighth floor.
他们在八楼
They're on the eighth floor.
斯维奇，直走
Switch, straight ahead.
（Apoc 一名取自圣经《启示录》apocalypse 中宣告末日的黑暗天使“天启”， 对应此处正是他交了尼奥第一把武器）
尼奥
Neo...
希望先知跟你说的是好消息
I hope the Oracle gave you some good news.
现在左转 那就是了
Now left. That's it.
很好
Good.
他们去哪了？
Where are they?
在墙壁里
They're in the walls.
在墙里！
In the walls!
是特工！
It's an agent!
墨菲斯！
Morpheus!
崔尼蒂 你们必须带上尼奥走！
Trinity. You must get Neo out!
-他才是最重要的人！ -不！
-He's all that matters! -No!
-不 墨菲斯 不要！ -崔尼蒂，快走！
-No, Morpheus! Don't! -Trinity, go!
Go!
-我们不能丢下他！ -我们只能这么做了！
-We can't leave him! -We have to!
赛弗，快来啊！
Cypher, come on!
伟大的墨菲斯 我们终于见面了
The great Morpheus. We meet at last.
你是哪位？
And you are?
史密斯
A Smith.
史密斯特工
Agent Smith.
我看你们长得都一样
You all look the same to me.
交给你们了
Take him.
No!
-接线员 -我需要出口，快
-Operator. -l need an exit, fast.
-塞弗？ -是我
-Cypher? -Yeah.
刚才发生了意外 天杀的车祸
There was an accident. Goddamn car accident.
突然就爆炸了
All of a sudden, boom.
我还困在这呢
Somebody up there still likes me.
找到你了
I got you.
赶紧把我弄出去
Just get me out of here fast.
最近的出口在Franklin和Erie的街口 是间老旧的电视修理店
Nearest exit, Franklin and Erie. An old TV repair shop.
Right.
-接线员 -坦克，是我
-Operator. -Tank, it's me.
墨菲斯还活着吗？
Is Morpheus alive?
墨菲斯还活着吗，坦克？
Is Morpheus alive, Tank?
活着 他被带走了 我不知道是去哪
Yes. They're moving him. l don 't know where.
他还活着 我们需要出口
He's alive. We need an exit.
你们离赛弗不远
You're not far from Cypher.
-赛弗？ -想不到吧
-Cypher? -I know.
-我让他去富兰克林和厄里街口了 -收到
-I sent him to Franklin and Erie. -Got it.
他回来了
Got him.
他们在哪？
Where are they?
正要接电话呢
Making the call.
很好
Good.
你先来，尼奥
You first, Neo.
该死！
Shit!
坦克！
Tank!
No!
我不知道 突然就断线了
I don't know. It just went dead.
你好啊，崔尼蒂
Hello, Trinity.
（Cypher 最古早的意思是"zero", 0，对应了他成为"the One", 1的对立面）
赛弗？ 坦克去哪了？
Cypher? Where's Tank?
你知道吗……
You know...
好久以来……
...for a long time...
我觉得自己爱上你了
...I thought I was in love with you.
我总是会梦到你
I used to dream about you.
你长得这么漂亮，崔尼蒂
You're a beautiful woman, Trinity.
真可惜只能落得这步田地
Too bad things had to turn out this way.
你杀了他们
You killed them.
-什么？ -天呐
-What? -Oh , God.
我厌倦了，崔尼蒂
I'm tired, Trinity.
我受够了这场战争……
I'm tired of this war...
受够了搏斗 受够了这艘船……
...tired of fighting. I'm tired of this ship...
受够了挨冻，还有每天吃那恶心的糊糊
...of being cold, of eating the same goddamn goop every day.
但最主要的是……
But most of all...
我受够了那个混蛋和他的屁话
...l'm tired of that jackoff and all of his bullshit.
想不到吧，混蛋！
Surprise, asshole!
没想到自己会有今天吧
I bet you never saw this coming...
是吧？
...did you?
天呐，我真希望能亲眼……
God, I wish I could be there...
看着他们打垮你
...when they break you.
我希望能在你崩溃的那一刻走过去
I wish I could walk in just when it happens...
这样一来……
...so right then...
你就会知道是我干的了
...you'd know it was me.
你把墨菲斯出卖给他们
You gave them Morpheus.
是他骗了我们，崔尼蒂
He lied to us, Trinity.
他把我们耍了！
He tricked us!
要是你早点告诉我们真相……
If you had told us the truth...
我们才不选他妈的红药丸呢！
...we would've told you to shove that red pill up your ass!
不是的，赛弗 他解放了我们
That is not true, Cypher. He set us free.
“解放” 你管这叫“解放”？
"Free." You call this free?
我每天就只能按他的指示行事
All I do is what he tells me to do.
要我在这里和矩阵之间选一个
If I had to choose between that and the Matrix...
我选择矩阵
...I choose the Matrix.
矩阵不是真实的
The Matrix isn't real.
我不这么看，崔尼蒂
I disagree, Trinity.
我认为矩阵……
I think the Matrix...
可以比这个世界更真实
...can be more real than this world.
只要我在这边拔个插头
All I do is pull the plug here.
那边……
But there...
你就得看着艾波克死
...you have to watch Apoc die.
Trinity.
-欢迎来到真实的世界 -可是你已经出来了，赛弗
-Welcome to the real world. -But you're out, Cypher.
-你回不去了 -不，那只是你以为的
-You can 't go back. -Oh, no. That's what you think.
他们会把我的身体重新接入
They'll reinsert my body.
我会睡去 等我在矩阵中醒来，什么玩意都不会记得
I go back to sleep. When l wake up, l won 't remember a goddame thing.
顺便提一句
By the way...
你要是你有什么要紧的话想对斯维奇说……
...if you have anything terribly important
to say to Switch...
最好现在就说吧
I suggest you say it now.
-哦不，求你不要这么做 -我不要像这样
-Oh. No, please don't. -Not like this.
（Switch 一名直译为“反转”，暗示之后的情节
另外，在导演最初的设计中，她是跨性别人士，真实性别为男性，矩阵中是女性/自我认同为女性）
不要像这样死去
Not like this.
太迟了
Too late.
你个天杀的，赛弗！
Goddamn you , Cypher!
别恨我，崔妮蒂
Don't hate me, Trinity.
我只是个提供情报的
I'm just a messenger.
现在，我要证明给你看
And right now, I'm going to prove it to you.
如果墨菲斯是对的……
If Morpheus was right...
那我就拔不掉这个插头
...there's no way I can pull this plug.
如果尼奥真是救世主
I mean if Neo's the One...
就一定会发生……
...then there'd have to be...
某个奇迹来阻止我
...some kind of a miracle to stop me.
是吧？
Right?
我是说，要是他死了……
I mean, how can he be the One...
还怎么做救世主啊？
...if he's dead?
你以前从没回答过我……
You never did answer me before...
你到底信不信墨菲斯的鬼话？
...if you bought into Morpheus' bullshit.
说嘛 我只想听信还是不信
Come on. All I want is a little yes or no.
看着他的眼睛……
Look into his eyes...
那双又大又迷人的眼睛
...those big, pretty eyes...
然后告诉我……
...and tell me...
信……
...yes...
……还是不信
...or no.
-我信 -不！
-Yes. -No!
我不相信
I don't believe it.
不管信不信，你个混蛋，你都是要被烧死的！
Believe it or not, you piece of shit, you're still going to burn!
你先走
You first.
-你受伤了 -我会没事的
-You're hurt. -I'll be all right.
多泽怎么样？
Dozer?
你有过就这么站在这儿凝视这它吗？
Have you ever stood and stared at it?
惊叹于它的美丽……
Marveled at its beauty...
它的天才？
...its genius?
数以亿计的人们……
Billions of people...
就在这里生活着
...just living out their lives.
一无所知
Oblivious.
你知不知道第一代矩阵……
Did you know that the first Matrix...
被设计成一个完美的人类世界 在那里无人受苦……
...was designed to be a perfect human world where none suffered...
人人都很幸福
...where everyone would be happy.
结果却是场灾难
It was a disaster.
没人能接受那个程序 一整茬“庄稼”都报废了
No one would accept the program. Entire crops were lost.
有些人认为……
Some believe that...
我们缺乏那种用来描述你们的完美世界的编程语言
...we lacked the programming language to describe your perfect world.
但是我相信……
But I believe that...
作为一个物种……
...as a species...
人类是靠苦难和……
...human beings define their reality through misery...
折磨来界定“真实”的
...and suffering.
因此那个完美的世界只是一个……
So the perfect world was a dream...
让你们那原始的大脑拼命想醒过来的梦
...that your primitive cerebrum kept trying to wake up from.
这就是为什么矩阵被重新设计成了这样
Which is why the Matrix was redesigned to this.
你们文明的巅峰……
The peak...
...of your civilization.
我得用"你们的文明"一词……
I say, "your civilization"...
因为一旦我们开始代替你们思考，这事实上就变成了我们的文明
...because as soon as we started thinking for you, it really became our civilization...
当然了，正是周围发生的这样
...which is, of course, what this is all about.
这就是进化，墨菲斯
Evolution, Morpheus.
进化
Evolution.
就好比恐龙的灭绝
Like the dinosaur.
看看窗外吧
Look out that window.
你们有过自己的时代
You had your time.
未来已是我们的天下，墨菲斯
The future is our world, Morpheus.
未来，是我们的时代
The future is our time.
可能出问题了
There could be a problem.
-他们要对他做什么？ -他们在入侵他的意识
-What are they doing to him? -They're breaking into his mind.
就跟黑入电脑一样 入侵成功只是时间问题
It's like hacking a computer. All it takes is time.
要花多久？
How much time?
取决于他的意志力 但头脑早晚会被撬开……
Depends on the mind. But eventually, it'll crack...
他的α脑电波就会变成这样
...and his alpha patterns will change from this to this.
到时候，他什么都会交代的
When it does, he'll tell them anything they want to know.
他们想要什么？
And what do they want?
每个舰长都有锡安主机的接入密钥
The leader of every ship is given codes to Zion's mainframe computer.
如果特工得到了密钥，进入了锡安主机
If an agent got the codes and got into Zion's mainframe...
我们就全完了 不能让这种事情发生
...they could destroy us. We can't let that happen.
崔尼蒂，锡安的重要性远远超过我……
Trinity, Zion's more important than me...
还有你……
...or you...
甚至是墨菲斯
...or even Morpheus.
一定还有什么我们可以做的
There has to be something we can do.
是的 拔掉插头
There is. We pull the plug.
你要杀了他？
You're gonna kill him?
杀死墨菲斯？
Kill Morpheus?
我们别无选择
We don't have any other choice.
永远不该让人类做机器的工作
Never send a human to do a machine's job.
如果线人真的失败了……
If indeed the insider has failed...
他们会尽快切断连接，除非……
...they'll sever the connection as soon as possible, unless---
他们全死了 不管怎样……
They're dead. In either case---
我们别无选择，只有按原计划进行 派出哨兵
We have no choice but to continue as planned. Deploy the sentinels.
立刻
Immediately.
墨菲斯，你不仅仅是我们的领袖
Morpheus, you were more than a leader to us.
更像是我们的父亲
You were a father.
我们会永远怀念你
We'll miss you always.
住手！
Stop!
我不敢相信这真的发生了
I don't believe this is happening.
-尼奥，必须这么做 -真的吗？
-Neo, this has to be done. -Does it?
我不知道 我……
I don't know. I...
-这不可能只是巧合 不可能 -你在说什么？
-This can't be just coincidence. It can't be... -What? What are you talking about?
先知
The Oracle.
她预言了这个
She told me this would happen.
她说过，我将不得不做出选择
She told me, that I would have to make a choice.
什么选择？
What choice?
-你要干什么？ -我要进去
-What are you doing? -I'm going in.
-不，你不可以 -我必须这么做
-No, you're not. -I have to.
尼奥，墨菲斯牺牲自己，就是让我们能带你出来
Neo, Morpheus sacrificed himself so that we could get you out.
绝不可以再让你回去
There is no way that you're going back in.
墨菲斯那么做是因为他错信了我的身份
Morpheus did what he did because he believed I'm something I'm not.
什么？
What?
我并不是救世主
I'm not the One, Trinity.
-先知说时我也很吃惊 -不，你必须是
-The Oracle hit me with that too. -No, you have to be.
很抱歉，我真的不是 我不过是个普通人
I'm sorry, I'm not. I'm just another guy.
不，尼奥，那不是真的
No, Neo, that's not true.
-不可能是真的 -为什么？
-It can't be true. -Why?
尼奥，这是发疯 他们把墨菲斯关在有军队把守的大楼里
Neo, this is Loco. They've got Morpheus in a military-controlled building.
即便你有办法进到楼里，也有特工在看守他 三个都在
Even if you somehow got inside, those are agents holding him. Three of them.
我也想要墨菲斯回来，但你就是在送死
I want Morpheus back too, but what you're talking about is suicide.
我知道看起来是这样
I know that's what it looks like...
但真的不是
...but it's not.
我没法跟你解释为什么
I can't explain to you why it's not.
墨菲斯有一个信念，他甚至愿意为此付出生命
Morpheus believed something, and he was ready to give his life for it.
现在我能理解他了 所以我必须去
I understand that now. That's why I have to go.
-为什么 -因为我只相信这件事
-Why? -Because I believe in something.
相信什么？
What?
我相信我能带他回来
I believe I can bring him back.
-你要干什么？ -跟你一起去
-What are you doing? -Going with you.
-不行 -“不行”？
-No, you're not. -"No"?
我来告诉你我相信什么
Let me tell you what I believe.
墨菲斯在我心中比在你心中还要重要
I believe Morpheus means more to me
than he does to you.
如果你真想救出他，你会需要我的帮助的
I believe if you are serious about saving him, you will need my help.
而且我现在是舰上的最高长官
And since I am the ranking officer on this ship...
你要是不喜欢这样，那就下地狱吧
...if you don't like it, I believe you can go to hell.
因为你也没别的地方去了
Because you aren't going anywhere else.
Tank...
让我们进去
...Load us up.
我想跟你分享一下我在这里
I'd like to share a revelation that I've had...
悟出的一个道理
...during my time here.
是我在试图给你们的物种分类时想到的
It came to me when I tried to classify your species...
我意识到……
...and I realized that...
你们根本算不上哺乳动物
...that you're not actually mammals.
这个星球上所有的哺乳动物……
Every mammal on this planet...
都本能地会与周围环境建立平衡
...instinctively develops an equilibrium with the surrounding environment.
你们人类却不会这样
But you humans do not.
你们每到一个地区，就开始繁殖
You move to an area and you multiply...
不停地繁殖，直到一切自然资源枯竭
...and multiply until every natural resource is consumed.
你们继续生存的唯一途径……
The only way you can survive...
就是扩散到另一个地方
...is to spread to another area.
这个星球上还有一个物种……
There is another organism on this planet...
采取了相同的生产模式
...that follows the same pattern.
知道是什么吗？
Do you know what it is?
病毒
A virus.
人类就是一种疾病
Human beings are a disease.
是地球之癌
A cancer of this planet.
你们就是瘟疫
You are a plague.
而我们……
And we...
则是解药
...are the cure.
好吧，你们还需要什么？
Okay, so what do you need?
除了奇迹之外
Besides a miracle.
枪
Guns.
很多的枪
Lots of guns.
Neo...
没有人干过这种事
No one has ever done anything like this.
这就是为什么我们能成功的
That's why it's going to work.
血清怎么不起作用呢？
Why isn't the serum working?
或许我们问错了问题
Perhaps we're asking the wrong questions.
让我一个人跟他谈谈
Leave me with him.
马上
Now.
撑住啊，墨菲斯
Hold on, Morpheus.
他们马上去救你了 快了
They're coming for you. They're coming.
能听见我说话吗，墨菲斯？
Can you hear me, Morpheus?
让我跟你……
I'm going to be honest...
坦白吧……
...with you.
我……
I...
恨透……
...hate...
这个地方了
...this place...
这个动物园
...this zoo...
这座监狱……
...this prison...
这种“现实”，你怎么叫它都行
...this reality, whatever you want to call it.
我再也受不了了
I can't stand it any longer.
这种气味
It's the smell.
如果真有这种东西的话
If there is such a thing.
我已经它被熏透了
I feel saturated by it.
我能……
I can...
闻到……
...taste...
你的恶臭
...your stink.
每次我闻到，我都担心自己被它传染
And every time I do, I fear that I have somehow been infected by it.
真是恶心
It's repulsive.
不是吗？
Isn't it?
我必须离开这里
I must get out of here.
我必须获得自由
I must get free.
而钥匙就在你的脑子里
And in this mind is the key.
我的钥匙
My key.
只要摧毁了锡安，我就不用再待在这儿了
Once Zion is destroyed, there is no need for me to be here.
你明白吗？
Do you understand?
我需要密钥
I need the codes.
我必须进入锡安……
I have to get inside Zion...
而你必须告诉我怎么做
...and you have to tell me how.
你要么告诉我
You're going to tell me...
要么就去死
...or you're going to die.
请拿掉身上所有的金属物品，钥匙，零钱
Please remove any metallic items you're carrying. Keys, loose change.
该死！
Holy shit!
支援，请求支援！
Backup. Send backup.
不许动！
Freeze!
你刚才在干什么？
What were you doing?
他还不知道呢
He doesn't know.
知道什么？
Know what?
看来他们是想救他
I think they're trying to save him.
根本没有勺子
There is no spoon.
找到并干掉他们！
Find them and destroy them!
我再重复一遍：我们受到了袭击！
I repeat: we're under attack!
崔尼蒂
Trinity!
帮帮我！
Help!
不过是凡人
Only human.
有种躲这个
Dodge this.
-你是怎么做到的？ -做到什么？
-How did you do that? -Do what?
你像他们那样躲子弹 我从来没见过谁能这么快
You moved like they do. I've never seen anyone move that fast.
还是不够快
It wasn't fast enough.
你会开那个吗？
Can you fly that thing?
现在还不会
Not yet.
接线员
Operator.
坦克 我需要B212直升机的飞行员程序
Tank. l need a pilot program for a B-212 helicopter.
要快
Hurry.
我们走
Let's go.
No.
墨菲斯，站起来 起来 快起来
Morpheus, get up. Get up, get up.
他跳不过来的
He's not going to make it.
抓住你了
Got you.
Trinity!
我就知道
I knew it.
他是救世主
He's the One.
你现在相信了吗，崔妮蒂？
Do you believe it now, Trinity?
可是墨菲斯……
Morpheus...
先知
The Oracle.
-她告诉我 -她所告诉你的……
-She told me--- -She told you...
只是你需要知道的
...exactly what you needed to hear.
仅此而已
That's all.
尼奥，早晚你会领会到，就像我一样地……
Neo, sooner or later you'll realize, just as I did...
——知道路在何方……
...there's a difference between knowing the path...
与真的践行了它，是不一样的
...and walking the path.
-接线员 -坦克
-Operator. -Tank.
-天呐，重新听到你声音真是太棒了，长官 -我们需要出口
-Goddamn. It's good to hear your voice, sir. -We need an exit.
准备好了 在地铁站里 State和Balboa站
Got one ready. Subway station, State and Balboa.
-该死的！ -追踪完毕
-Damn it! -The trace was completed.
-找到他们的位置了 -哨兵已准备就绪
-We have their position. -Sentinels are standing by.
下令攻击吧
Order the strike.
他们还没出去呢
They're not out yet.
你先来，墨菲斯
You first, Morpheus.
尼奥，有件事我想告诉你……
Neo, I want to tell you something...
但我怕一说出口会发生什么事
...but I'm afraid of what it could mean if I do.
先知告诉我的事情都成真了
Everything the Oracle told me has come true.
除了一件事
Everything but this.
除了什么？
But what?
尼奥！
Neo!
-到底出了什么事？ -是特工
-What the hell just happened? -An agent.
-你得送我回去 -我做不到的
-You have to send me back. -I can't.
安德森先生
Mr. Anderson.
跑啊，尼奥 快跑
Run, Neo. Run.
他是在做什么？
What is he doing?
他开始相信了
He's beginning to believe.
你没子弹了
You're empty.
你也一样
So are you.
我会很享受地看着你死去
I'm going to enjoy watching you die...
安德森先生
...Mr. Anderson.
上帝啊，他会活活打死他的
Jesus, he's killing him.
听见了吗，安德森先生？
You hear that, Mr. Anderson?
那儿传来的就是你的宿命
That is the sound of inevitability.
你的丧钟
It is the sound of your death.
再见了，安德森先生
Goodbye, Mr. Anderson.
我的名字……
My name...
是尼奥
...is Neo.
怎么了？ 我不知道 我追踪不到他了
What happened? I don't know. I lost him.
该死
Oh , shit.
哨兵来了
Sentinels.
-还有多久？ -五六分钟吧
-How long? -Five, maybe six minutes.
坦克，给EMP充能
Tank, charge the EMP.
-他出来之前我们不能用 -我知道，崔尼蒂 别担心
-We can't use that until he's out. -I know, Trinity. Don't worry.
他能行的
He's gonna make it.
平底鞋还是高跟鞋? 不，你就……
Flat or pumps? No, just---
什么鬼？ 那是我的手机！
What the shit? That's my phone!
那家伙抢了我的手机！
That guy took my phone!
找到他了！ 他正在逃跑
Got him! He's on the run.
魔法师先生，带我离开这儿！
Mr. Wizard, get me out of here!
有个旧出口 Wabash和Lake街的路口
I got an old exit. Wabash and Lake.
Oh, shit!
帮帮我！ 我需要一点帮助！
Help! Need a little help!
那扇门
The door.
左手边的门
The door on your left.
不，是另一个左边！
No, your other left!
走后门
The back door.
哦不
Oh, no.
它们来了
Here they come.
他能做到的
He's going to make it.
（303号房是开场崔尼蒂出现的地方，情节由此形成闭环）
从巷子尽头的逃生梯上去 在303号房
The fire escape at the end of the alley, room 303.
它们进来了
They're inside.
快点啊，尼奥
Hurry, Neo.
这不可能
It can't be.
检查一下
Check him.
他死了
He's gone.
再见了，安德森先生
Goodbye, Mr. Anderson.
尼奥……
Neo...
我不再害怕了
I'm not afraid anymore.
先知告诉我……
The Oracle told me that...
我会爱上那个男人，我爱上的人会成为救世主
...I'd fall in love with that man, the man that I loved would be the One.
所以你看……
So you see...
你不能死
...you can't be dead.
你不能……
You can't be...
因为我爱上的是你
...because I love you.
你能听见吗？
You hear me?
我爱你
I love you.
现在，站起来
Now, get up.
不
No.
怎么会？
How?
他就是救世主
He is the One.
尼奥！
Neo!
（呼叫传输选择：收到）
我知道你就在那里
I know you're out there.
（警告：运营商异常）
我能感觉到你
I can feel you now.
（追踪程序：运行中）
我知道你害怕我们
I know that you're afraid. You're afraid of us.
你害怕改变
You're afraid of change.
（系统崩溃）
我无法预知未来
I don 't know the future.
我不是来告诉你 这一切将如何结束的
I didn 't come here to tell you how this is going to end.
我是来告诉你 一切将如何开始
I came here to tell you how it's going to begin.
我要挂掉这通电话了
I'm going to hang up this phone.
然后我将向人们展示你不想告诉他们的一切
And then I'll show these people what you don 't want them to see.
我将让他们看到一个……
I'm going to show them a world...
没有你们的世界
...without you.
一个没有规则和控制，没有界限和尽头的世界
A world without rules and controls, without borders or boundaries.
在那里一切皆有可能
A world where anything is possible.
之后我们将走向何处……
Where we go from there...
选择权在你手中
...is a choice I leave to you.